Mustafa Akbari

Software Engineer

Email: <u>Akbarimustafa64@gmail.com</u> | Phone: 00491795253045 | Birth date: 06.12.1991 | Address: Am Steinfeld 3, 85659 Forstern, Germany LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mustafa-akbari-289543219/ | GitHub: https://github.com/ci-mustafa

Executive Summary

Experienced IT professional with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and over 5 years in IT administration, database management, and web development. Proven ability to solve problems and communicate effectively. Currently advancing skills through a Full Stack Development program at Code Institute. Seeking to contribute to and grow within a development team.

Technical Skillset

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Containers	APIs	Operating sys	VC sys
Python JavaScript CSS3 HTML5	MySQL Postgres	Django jQuery Bootstrap Flask Jest Pytest	Docker	Restfull API	Windows Linux	Git Github

Work Experience

November 2022- January 2024

Freelancer (Backend Development)

Spottech, New Zealand

- Development and implementation of backend functions for various applications
- Integrated API endpoints and developed database-driven functions using Django, resulting in a 45% increase in data processing speed and reducing server response time by 30%
- Designed and developed robust backend infrastructure, enhancing system performance by 40% and reducing latency by 25%, ensuring seamless operations and improving user experience across all platforms
- Consistently optimize and maintain applications to uphold high standards of performance and quality
- Effectively improved and optimized SQL databases, resulting in a 30% improvement in query performance and a 20% reduction in storage costs, while ensuring high availability to meet end-user requirements for over 1,000 users

March 2017–October 2020

Database Administrator

UHCC, Afg

- Designed and created databases using MySQL, and integrated with third-party applications via MySQL Workbench
- Maintained database standards and policies, achieving 99.9% uptime
- Managed database availability and performance, ensuring 99.9% uptime and more than 50% faster query execution
- Implemented event triggers for problem detection, reducing issue resolution time by 40%
- Performed database maintenance and optimization, improving performance by 55%
- Monitor usage and security

February 2015-January 2017

IT Administrator

TMB, Afg

- Troubleshot network issues, reducing downtime by 20%
- Managed and maintained printers, copiers, and fax machines for 100+ users
- Conducted server maintenance and implemented disaster recovery plans, achieving 99.9% data availability
- Monitored UPS workstations and operational printers, ensuring 95% uptime
- Provided backup support for workflow systems, enhancing reliability by 30%
- Ensured password and data security in desktop environments, resulting in a 50% decrease in security incidents

Education

February 2024–Present Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

December 2020—August 2022 Skills Enhancement Udemy, Code with Mosh (online resources)

November 2010 – December 2014 Bachelor of Computer Science Aria University

Certifications

Bachelor of Computer Science
Code Institute - Fullstack Web Development – on going
Code with Mosh – Complate Django (16 hours)
Udemy – 100 Days of Code (54 hours)
Python Programming Masterclass (63 hours)

Language Skills

Good German Fluent English Fluent Turkish Native Persion